Inventory of the John P. Lake papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John P. Lake papers
1934-1980
85045
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Orders, reports, personnel records, certificates, and photographs, relating to American military assistance to Chinese forces during World War II, and to attempted American mediation between Kuomintang and Chinese communist forces in 1946.
Lake, John P., 1894-1976.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Colonel and commanding officer in the United States Army with the Combat Section in the Chinese 18th Army, Chinese Combat Command, 1945. Received Award of Legion of Merit in 1945 and Army Commendation Ribbon in 1946 for exceptionally meritorious conduct in the performance of outstanding services as Chairman of Executive Headquarters Field Team No. 7 in Tsinan, China. The Executive Headquarters was charged with Implementing the cessation of civil strife in China, the restoration of communications, and the reorganization of the Chinese Army. Lake retired from the Army in 1953.
Scope and Content of Collection
Orders, reports, personnel records, correspondence, certificates, and photographs, relating to American military assistance to Chinese forces during World War II, and to attempted American mediation between Kuomintang and Chinese communist forces in 1946.
United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Army. Forces in China Theater.; China--History--Civil War, 1945-1949.; United States--Armed Forces--China.; World War, 1939-1945--China.
- Correspondence, 1945-1980 (Box 1)
- Notes, Documentation, and Correspondence, undated (Box 1)
- Interview with Yasui Mitsuru concerning activities in Japan, 1949 (Box 1)
- Marriage, Death, and Retirement Records, 1947-1976 (Box 1)
- Official Army Records Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1)
- Special Orders, 1945-1975 (Box 1)
- Court Martial Documentation, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
- General Court Martial Cases, 1951 (Box 1)
- A History of the Executive Headquarters in Peiping China, 1947 (Box 1)
- Immigration Materials, 1945 (Box 1)
- Japanese Print of Trout, 1952 (Box 1)
- Business Cards, undated (Box 1)
- Army Navy Football Game Program, 1934 (Box 2)
- Photo of John P. Lake, undated (Box 2)
- Portrait, undated (Box 2)
- Photos labeled "Old China" (3 folders), Ca. 1944-1946 (Box 2)
- Portraits of John P. Lake, 1952 (Box 2)
- Photo Album, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook Journal, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Loose Photos removed from Scrapbook Journal, undated (Box 2)
  - Items removed from Scrapbook Journal (Box 2)
- Photos from Envelope, 1939-1972 (Box 2)
- Army Commendation Certificate, 1946 (Box 3)
- Family Photo Album, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
  - Loose Photos from Family Photo Album, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
- Photo Album of Military Career, undated (Box 3)
  - Loose Photos removed from Photo Album of Military Career, undated (Box 3)
- Cloth Map of China, 1944 (Box 4)
- Photo Album of Japan from Konoye Murooka, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Loose Photos Removed from Photo Album, 1969 (Box 4)
- Official Document, undated (Box 4)